# losif V.

# Senior Software Engineer

London, UK

in iosify 🞧 iosify 🚵 iosify

I am a Senior Software Engineer with extensive experience in developing end-to-end projects using Node.js and Laravel. I prioritise writing clean, maintainable code to ensure ease of maintenance and quick onboarding for junior developers. With a natural curiosity and a commitment to continuous learning, I am always exploring new technologies and methodologies to enhance my skills and contribute effectively to my team and stakeholders. I'm currently learning T3Stack, NextJS, tRPC, Drizzle ORM, with Vercel.

#### SKILLS

| Languages |                    |  |     | Frameworks |         |            |  | Dev-Ops |           |        |  |
|-----------|--------------------|--|-----|------------|---------|------------|--|---------|-----------|--------|--|
| Node.js   | Node.js Javascript |  |     | Laravel    | Express | Serverless |  | AWS     | Terraform | CI/CD  |  |
| Typescrip | Typescript PHP     |  | ity | Hardhat    |         |            |  | Githuk  | Actions   | Vercel |  |
| bash      |                    |  |     |            |         |            |  | Docke   | r         |        |  |

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE (4)**

Aug 2018 - Current

### **Contractor Software Engineer** at Casa4 (own LTD)

Provided contractor services through my own LTD, Casa4, in between other roles. The following is a list of the most notable projects, specializing in Laravel and Node.js. Involved both in team-based development and solo application building from design to deployment and maintenance.

- Artetra: As an acting CTO, I was responsible with converting business requirements into project features by overseeing the application architecture. I managed a team of 3-4 developers and provided them with necessary assistance.
- ElectroRent: Developed and maintained Laravel code to fix bugs and add new features for a tool-renting platform.
- Aliat Optic: Designed and developed an invoicing app, integrating external FTP data via AWS Lambda and DynamoDB. This application was successfully used in production for about 3 years with minimal maintenance, demonstrating reliability and efficiency.
- Hurlingham Club: Led the migration of systems to internal servers, resolving various DevOps issues.
- TicketTailor: Improved the API of a large ticketing application by fixing bugs and adding new features.
- → Technologies: Laravel, Node.js, React, AWS Lambda, MySQL, Terraform, AWS, VueJS, NextJS, CLI, Bash

Oct 2020 - Aug 2022

# Software Engineer at True Compliance

Contributed to the development of a cloud-based compliance management system, enhancing compliance tracking and reporting capabilities.

- Developed the main API of the system and contributed to designing the ecosystem's serverless architecture, leading to a robust and scalable solution.
- Created a reporting application that enabled non-technical stakeholders to preview any key metrics.

- Also built a bespoke real-time caching system that stores processed relational data in a NoSQL database.
   The purpose of this was to vastly increase the speed of the system and reduce the load on the database.
- → Technologies: Laravel, Laravel Vapor, AWS, VueJS, Node.js, Serverless Framework, CLI, Bash

Oct 2018 - Oct 2019

# Software Engineer at Skin Analytics

Designed and developed main applications and maintained AWS infrastructure, contributing to the company's mission of improving skin health.

- Led the migration from a NoSQL database to a relational database, resulting in an 11x speed increase without affecting the frontend or user experience.
- → Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, TypeScript, AWS, Loopback, pm2, Angular

Feb 2017 - Jun 2018

# Application Developer / Dev-Ops at Woooba

Sole Backend Engineer responsible for designing, developing, and supporting client applications, driving business growth.

- Developed and maintained nationwide educational platforms, enhancing the learning experience for thousands of users.
- Built a comprehensive financial management application with Laravel and Vue.
- Managed all DigitalOcean droplets with a CI setup ensuring reliable and efficient deployment processes.
- → Technologies: Laravel, DigitalOcean, Laravel Forge, MySql, VueJS

#### PROJECTS (2) -

#### **CLI Path**

Simple CLI tool to search paths on google maps (Serverless Framework, Auth0, OpenAPI, VHS)

## Casa4 website

An overengineered personal website built for learning purposes (Hugo, Terraform, Cloudfront, AWS, GHA)

#### **EDUCATION (2)** -

2010 - 2012

Masters Management and Business Engineering at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

2004 - 2009

Masters Computer Science at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

#### INTERESTS -

# **Hobbies**

Motorcycles Photography
Chess HiFi Audio Boxing